It's been three years since I last saw Ellen.
I've visited the Vankreift
family numerous times.
However...
Your Highness.
Although you've come all this way,
I regret to inform you
that Lady Ellen is not here again today.
I see.
Not once have I been able to see her.
Please, come inside.
Would you like something to drink?
Thank you.
Now, now, right this way.
Recently, Roren has started
welcoming us into the mansion.
He must be feeling guilty
for disappointing us every time.
It's also... probably to convince us
that Ellen really isn't here.
This tea is always so delicious.
I wonder when we'll ever meet...
Who are you guys?
And you are?
The daughter of Sauvel Vankreift,
the lord of this estate.
So, who are you guys?
Did Roren not tell you?
Of course not!
Gramps doesn't tell me or my mother anything.
Now, why are you here?
We came to see Ellen.
Ellen again?
Even I haven't seen her.
What? Not even you have?
That's right! All everyone talks
about is Ellen this, Ellen that!
Why does everyone want to see her, anyway?
I wanted to apologize in person.
Hmm...
Wait, are you the one always bringing gifts?
Huh?
Then bring me some too!
Your Highnesses, would you care
for some more tea?
Hold it! Did you just say "Your Highnesses"?
You guys are princes?!
Lady Rafilia, mind how
you speak to His Highness.
D-Don't laugh at me!
Yes, I'm sorry.
My sincere apologies.
No, I don't mind.
Rafilia.
The next time I come by,
I'll be sure to bring you something.
Yay!
Lady Rafilia, please mind your manners.
Roren, thank you for your
hospitality. I'll come again.
Of course.
The prince said he'd bring me something!
Lady Rafilia...
How many times must I tell you?!
Ah, I'm sorry!
Brother, you seem to be enjoying yourself.
I am. No one's ever spoken
to me like that before.
Wasn't she just being brash?
THE CURSE OF THE MINES
You look cuter than ever today,
my little princess!
You're rather dressed up.
I'm going to visit Uncle's mine
to greet everyone,
so I thought I ought to be properly prepared.
My, my! I see even you
get nerves, sweet Ellen.
W-Well... it's just...
Princess, are you heading somewhere?
Van!
Fluffy!
Father and I are going out to assist Uncle.
Are you all right, princess?
She's just nervous.
Then I shall accompany her!
Van, you're not ready yet.
You have to be able to humanize.
You're right.
All right, let's go, Ellen.
Yes, Father!
Oh...
We're off, Mother!
I'll see you later.
See you again, Van!
The princess hasn't played
with me at all lately.
And here we've been doing it
since she was little...
Van!
Fwuffy!
Ah, Ellen, that's dangerous!
Come now, why don't you
come back with Daddy?
No! Lemme go!
- No! Lemme go!
- What should we play?
Hmm, maybe it's too soon for hide and seek.
Oh...
Wha?!
Van!
Huh?
Van, what do ya wanna pway?
How about hide and seek, pwincess?
She already knows the teleportation spell?
Ellen! Where are you, Ellen?!
Cry.
Van!
Ellen!
Father, weggo of Van!
Lord Rovel...
What are you doing to my child?!
Didn't expect to lure you out too, Vint.
It's what I do to bring Ellen out of hiding.
Sorry for the fuss.
I can't believe you'd do that to my child...
- I don't care who you are!
- I wuv you!
My bad. I said sorry.
Cut me some slack, will you?
I wuv you!
Indeed, I must learn to humanize at once.
The princes visited again?
Yes, Your Grace.
However, I informed them of Lady Ellen's
absence and they returned home.
That's good. It is the truth, after all.
Brother, the mine we're looking into today
originally produced a lot of silver.
However, it's seen a steep decline of late.
Because of that and other inevitable
circumstances, I've decided to close the mine.
That's what I intend to tell them.
I see.
Now then, Ellen.
The mines are dangerous,
so stay with your father, okay?
Not that I think he'd
let you run off on your own.
Of course not!
I'll be carrying her the whole time.
What?
Your pawpaw wishes he could accompany you too!
I'll bring back a souvenir, okay?
I shall be waiting!
By the way, is Grammie not here?
That's correct. I didn't tell her
you'd be here today.
Huh? Why not?
Because she'd demand we
take her to the mines with us.
Most likely.
By the way, Brother, about those...
The ingots that Ellen created for us.
Oh, those.
I was thinking of just saying
they came from an old vault.
If we say that they've been in the family,
not even the royal family would bat an eye.
Good thinking.
Huh?
There are too many carriages,
wouldn't you say?
That's strange...
You're far too green to try and outsmart me!
Especially concerning the mine closure!
Grammie?! Are you coming with us too?
That's right, Ellen, dear!
Alberto!
I am terribly sorry, my lords!
I am so happy to be
on an outing with you, Ellen.
It's like going on a picnic,
don't you think, Grammie?
I know, right?
It would appear Mother
is dead set on going...
Yeah.
Alberto.
We're counting on you.
Yes, my lords.
How dare you treat me like baggage.
I accompanied your father on inspections
before either of you were even born!
You don't say.
My apologies.
So that's why you're...
Grammie, I came in a dress.
You'll be fine, Ellen, dear.
Rovel plans on carrying you
the whole time anyway, right?
Of course!
Seriously?!
Lord Rovel, Lord Sauvel! Welcome!
Lord Rovel, it's been so long!
I heard you were coming with Lord Sauvel
today and couldn't wait to see you!
I knew it. I feel so out of place.
I've blown it.
What a terrible first impression.
My name is Ellen Vankreift.
I am Rovel Vankreift's daughter.
Goodness, Lord Rovel!
Isn't she adorable?!
Er, yes.
I've brought my brother here today
to discuss the closure of the mine.
So we really can't stay open, then...
Everyone!
Milady?
Lady Isabella!
It's been too long!
My, familiar faces!
You're about to talk business
with my sons, correct?
Before that...
I thought we might have some lunch,
so I came prepared.
Ah, this reminds me of when
the late duke used to visit.
You're right! He used to bring
good food when he came too.
We always looked forward to it.
Father must've had his heart
stolen through his stomach.
For certain.
Yep, yep.
Ellen, dear.
You should know that food
is the best way to win people over.
Grammie!
Ah, that was delicious...
Thank you so much, milady.
You boys still have healthy appetites!
I'm glad to see it.
They said this was originally
a silver mine, but...
As I suspected, there's a lot of quartz here.
Are you having fun?
Oh, yes!
I just love minerals.
Is that so?
Yes!
Oh...
There's plenty,
so feel free to look all you want.
Listen to this, Lady Isabella!
Way back when, this guy
used to eat my share too!
You know that's not true!
Whaddaya mean it's not true?!
I just ate what was leftover!
I see. To everyone here, this place is...
What's that supposed to mean?
Oh, I know!
If this mine is so rich in quartz,
it's bound to have silver over gold.
Atomic number 47...
This white stone is so beautiful!
Huh?
When you change the angle,
it's fun to see it sparkle!
What? Did you just say it sparkles?
Yes!
Don't tell me...
Your Grace, may I please break
this stone and check inside?
S-Sure.
That's...
What is it?
It's silver.
Silver? That's silver?
It's silver, Your Grace!
There may be more!
W-Wait a minute!
We can keep mining in these mountains!
Huh?
Ellen...
Yikes.
Your Grace! There's no need to close down!
We can still—
I said to wait!
Have you men already forgotten?
These mines are cursed by the spirits
because we've mined too much silver!
Cursed?
So it's time...
So that's what's going on.
Father, Uncle Sauvel.
May I speak with the men for just a bit?
My knowledge may be able
to help them in some way.
All right.
Everyone, does the curse happen to involve
people coming down with symptoms
such as shortness of breath, coughing,
and phlegm, possibly fatal in some cases?
How did you know?
Your curse... I have a feeling
I may know the cause of it.
Huh? She does?
For many years, you've all been
breathing in fine minerals and dust here.
That's had adverse effects on your bodies.
In other words,
this isn't the work of a spirit.
It a disease called pneumoconiosis.
Pneumoconiosis?
It's not a curse?
- There's no curse?
- First I've heard of it.
A disease, you say?
So, this "pneumoconiosis"... Is it curable?
I'm sorry. It's not possible
to rid you of it completely.
That said, with time, we can get you
some relief little by little.
Is that true?
If I could get the slightest relief from this
illness I've suffered from for so long...
I would be grateful. Please, help us.
Ellen?
Father, let us first return to the mansion.
I would like to discuss
something with you and Mother.
Ori too?
Yes.
Everyone, please allow me some time.
I'll discuss this with my mother,
and we're going to come up with a solution!
So, Ellen, can you truly treat this disease?
In theory.
In theory?
It's been too long since
the initial onset of their symptoms.
Furthermore, when lung disease
yields complications,
treatment becomes less certain.
Complications?
That's when the first disease
causes another to develop.
You're knowledgeable
on many difficult subjects.
What I know about the disease
is meaningless if I can't treat it.
But you already told them you could.
That's where I'd like to ask Mother for a favor.
Me?
Yes. I'm thinking of creating a medicine.
Wait! Can you really do something
like that, Ellen, dear?
I'm thinking it may be possible
if I change the way I use my powers.
Yet I can't shake the feeling
that doing this may have
an impact on the human world.
Ori, what do you think?
Well, why not let Ellen do as she pleases?
Huh?
Come now!
Yes, she may still be immature as a spirit.
But she won't know how her powers affect
this world unless she tries, now will she?
What?
Ori! If something happens to Ellen, I...
Oh, it'll be fine.
If anything happens, we just won't
come back to the human world.
What?! No, that won't do! Absolutely not!
Ellen, sweetie, this is your project.
You told everyone you could do it, didn't you?
So you should do it.
Yes, ma'am!
However, if you run into any problems,
you have to consult us.
Don't ever forget.
You've got me, your father,your grammie,
and your uncle to rely on.
Give it your all!
I guess my hands are tied...
I'll do my best!
Ori! Ellen's been holed up
for days and hasn't come out yet!
You think she's all right?!
It seems she hasn't been eating much either.
She probably hasn't even been sleeping!
No, I'm sure she hasn't!
She must be working really hard on that
medicine, so don't you go bothering her.
But...!
She's fine. Let's have faith
and be patient, okay?
What's wrong, Van?
She said I'm not allowed in there either.
You got locked out too, eh?
Ellen always gets tunnel vision
when she immerses herself in something.
That is true.
When she first discovered her spirit
power to manipulate the elements...
Ah, Ellen!
She didn't yet know how
to use or control her ability.
The princess has changed since then, but...
I can't take it anymore.
Oh, but Ori said not to...
Still, I'm worried!
But if I open the door, Ori will...
Ah, I'm worried! I'm so worried!
Princess! Princess!
Ah, that's it!
Let me at it, Van!
I can't take it anymore!
Huh?
Oh, Ori placed a barrier, did she?!
In that case...
The various chemical formulas
showing the structure of every
drug I knew in my past life!
If I can write down as many
as I can remember, then...
Ellen! Stop this right now!
Ellen!
Princess!
Are you all right, Ellen?!
The medicine...
It's done.
Ellen...
You're burning up!
To think you pushed yourself to this point...